Welcome back to AP US History in under
three minutes. No time for intros, let's
get into it. Topic 2.5 is all about the
interactions between Native Americans
and Europeans and how it changed from my
last video on topic 1.6. The basic thing
to know is that even before European
contact, Native American tribes always
fought each other. Now we start seeing
Native American groups ally with
European countries in an attempt to once
again fight against other tribes. But
even though this did happen, we still
see Europeans expand and encroach on
Native American land. With a prime
example being Metacom's War, also known
as King Philip's War, which was the
bloodiest battle in American history
relative to the population of the time.
This war started because English
colonists broke treaties made with the
natives and continued to forcefully
expand past the natives' land. And with
the killings of a few people along with
some other reasons, the war began. King
Philip was with the Native Americans and
fought against the colonists along with
a few Native American tribes. In the
end, it was said that over 7,000 people
died and the colonists ended up winning.
The effect of the end of this war was
the sort of end of Native American power
in the New England colonies. Though most
all Native American resistances failed,
there were a few that succeeded. One of
which was the Pueblo Revolt where the
indigenous Pueblo peoples successfully
revolted against the Spanish. The
aftermath of this was that it led to the
Spanish accommodation of some aspects of
American Indian culture in the
Southwest. But this would end not really
mattering as decades later the Spanish
would end up taking the land of the
Pueblo peoples. Here's some AP style
questions for this topic.
Here are the answers.
I'll see you in the next one.